Ishwar Sawale

COMPUTER VISION & DEEP LEARNING RESEARCHER

💌 ishwarsawale@gmail.com | 🎢 ishwarsawale.com | 🖸 ishwarsawale | 🛅 ishwarsawale | 💆 @ishwarsawale

Summary

I have 3.3+ years of experience in Data Science. I am currently working with Mindstix Software Labs as a Data Scientist/ML Engineer.

I am Research Engineer focus on data-driven solutions for Deep Learning, Computer Vision and Chat Bot based systems.

Before Mindstix, I was working with Coriolis Technologies Pvt Ltd for two years as a Machine Learning Engineer.

I also have completed 115+ courses related to Machine Learning, Al from Udemy, Coursera, Datacamp, & LinkedIn Learning.

Education

Diploma in Big Data Analytics

CDAC-ACTS PUNE Aug 2015 - Feb. 2016

• Achieved grade A with 70.00%

Bachelor of Engineering

University Of Pune Aug. 2011 - May. 2014

Achieved Distinction with 69.33%

Work Experience & Responsibility ___

Mindstix Software Labs

DATA SCIENTIST Feb. 2018 - PRESENT

Computer Vision Research

- Computer vision Research
- Question & Answer ChatBot Research
- · Deep Learning Algorithm Research
- Algorithm Design

Coriolis Technologies

Pune, India

Pune, India

Pune, India

Pune, India

MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Deep Learning Algorithm Design
- License Plate Recognition, Face Recognition

Projects

Chatbot HR

Mindstix Software Labs Project

Python, TensorFlow, RASA

Feb 2018 - Present

- I have created the Natural Language understanding framework for entity recognition, intent classification & dialogue management.
- I have developed a context-based retrieval framework to retrieve data from web pages.
- I have trained Natural Language Understanding model using Tensorflow word embeddings. For Dialogue management, I have developed the LSTM type of Neural Network.

Color Constancy Algorithm

Mindstix Software Labs Project

PYTHON, OPENCV, DLIB, CNN

Feb 2018 - Feb 2019

- I have developed an algorithm to approximate the accurate skin tone color of the person using one image.
- This algorithm uses a propriety method to color correct the image.
 Accuracy of the developed algorithm compared with spectrophotometer is less than 3.5 deltaE.

Face Recognition System

Mindstix Software Labs Project

FACENET, DLIB, SVM, KNN, PYTHON

Feb 2018 - April 2018

- I have used Transfer learning for Face recognition using pre-trained models like Facenet, Dlib.
- I have developed a web application to collect face data from users & sends collected data to the pipeline for further processing.

License Plate Recognition System

Coriolis Tech Project

OPENCV, DEEP LEARNING, PYTHON

March 2016 - Feb 2017

- I have developed the License Plate Recognition system using Convolution Neural Network.
- I have used the object detection pre-trained model to detect the car.
 For License plate recognition, I have trained Convolution Neural Network which generated bounding box after the discovery.
- For letter & alphabet detection, I have implemented CNN architecture which predicts each character independently of others.

Skills & Courses_

Tools Git, LaTeX

Stacks MongoDB, MySQL

Languages Python

Machine Learning Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch

PyImageSearch

• PylmageSearch Gurus Graduate by PylmageSearch

Coursera

- Structuring Machine Learning Projects by deeplearning.ai
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization by deeplearning,ai
- Recommender Systems: Evaluation and Metrics
- Nearest Neighbor Collaborative Filtering
- Matrix Factorization and Advanced Techniques
- Introduction to Recommender Systems: Non-Personalized and Content-Based
- Fundamentals of Digital Image and Video Processing by Northwestern University
- PCA by Imperial College London
- Multivariate Calculus by Imperial College London
- Linear Algebra by Imperial College London
- Mathematics for Machine Learning, a 3-course specialization by Imperial College London
- How Google does Machine Learning by Google Cloud

Datacamp

- Machine Learning with Python Track
- Data Scientist with Python Track
- Data Manipulation with Python Track
- Data Analyst with Python Track
- Importing & Cleaning Data with Python Track
- Data Scientist with R Track
- Data Analyst with R Track
- Importing & Cleaning Data with R Track
- Machine Learning with R Track

MAY 11, 2019 ISHWAR SAWALE · RÉSUMÉ